#### **JULIUS MARKAUSKAS**

Fort Mill, SC 29715 | Cell: 224-249-9645 | E-mail: juliusmar@gmail.com https://lt.linkedin.com/in/julius-markauskas-795aa0103

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

Team management skills. Preventative and predictive maintenance. Digital print equipment repair/maintenance. LEAN Manufacturing.

Digital Printing - Xerox, MGI, Oce, Riso, Durst, I-Image Testing and troubleshooting.

Problem identification, analysis. MS Office proficient, Adobe suite experience.

Computer repair/maintenance. Knowledge of various print finishing operations and equipment.

Languages English, Russian, Lithuanian.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### The M&R Companies – Roselle, IL

08/2016 - Present

Manufactures screen printing equipment for graphic and textile industries.

## **Digital Service Technician**

- Equipment malfunction identification, onsite service and maintenance.
- New equipment installation and customers training.
- Develop repair instructions.
- Troubleshooting over the phone.
- Training incoming new technicians.

# Modagrafics – Rolling Meadows, IL

03/2016 - 08/2016

# **Digital print operator**

- Operate and maintained the printing machinery.(durst rho 320r)
- Set up and operate cutting, collating, and laminating equipment.
- Undertook repairs of equipment in case of any defects or malfunctioning.
- Monitored quantity and quality of the end products and ensured they match the specifications.

## Littelfuse - Kaunas Plant, Lithuania

10/2013 - 11/2015

Manufactures advanced electromechanical products, primarily sensors and switches used in the automotive industry.

## **Facility Maintenance Manager**

- Hired as Equipment Maintenance Engineer, promoted in April, 2014.
- Managed two teams: Building and infrastructure maintenance and Manufacturing equipment maintenance. Supervised 16 employees.
- Managed the day-to-day activities of the equipment maintenance, support on new buildings construction.
- Developed useful maintenance KPIs (Key Performance Indicators) to improve equipment preventative maintenance and create MS Excel sheets to make an analysis for these KPI. Issued changes to preventative maintenance procedure.
- Developed maintenance budget, assured budget and expenses control.
- Trained department employees according to 5S principles, and created 5S sustainability program.
- Trained in LEAN Manufacturing program, and Successful Management courses.
- Equipment malfunction identification, service and maintenance organization.

- Ordering necessary spare parts and quantity control.
- Create preventative maintenance instructions and preventative maintenance plans for technicians.

#### VitaeLitera – Kaunas, Lithuania

10/2008 - 11/2015

Books, photo books, plastic cards and other unique print solutions.

#### **Digital Printing Engineer / Computer Technician**

- Pre-press and variable data files preparation. Print templates creation. (Adobe Suite, Microsoft Office, Creo Preps 5, CorelDraw, PrintShop Mail).
- Performed digital print equipment maintenance and service (MGI Meteor DP60).
- Operated and trained new operators on digital printing and finishing equipment (MGI Meteor DP60, Xerox D110, MGI PressCard Pro, MGI PunchCard Pro).
- Computer maintenance, software installation and update. Assisted employees having hardware, software, and networking issues.

Kaunas University of Technology – Publishing House, Lithuania 06/2001 – 10/2013 Electronic and printed study books, science journals and other print solutions.

# **E-publishing and Digital Printing Manager**

- Hired as Digital Printing Engineer/Computer Technician, promoted in October, 2005.
- Created and controlled department plans, managed work flow.
- Managing the launch of e-books web page www.ebooks.ktu.lt.
- Managing the launch of instant book price calculation on web page for customers www.web2print.lt.
- Managing the launch of digital press equipment statistic web journal http://lyderis.dakra.lt/aparatas.
- Created internal documents work flow system on MS excel and Google spreadsheet.
- Trained and consulted new users on how to prepare files for e-publishing (Adobe suite, CorelDraw).
- Trained new operators on digital print and finishing equipment.
- Computer maintenance, software installation and update. Assisted employees having hardware, software, and networking issues.
- Digital printing, prepress operator.(Xerox DC5252, DC12, DC3535, Nuvera120, Docutech65, 4100, 2101, Riso RP370, Oce 3165).
- Print finishing operator (Duplo DC-645 slitter/cutter, MGI PressCard Pro, MGI PunchCard Pro, Adast Maxima MS 80 B guillotine, Angraf B 704 creaser, Plockmatic 310+ Collator).

#### **EDUCATION**

| Master's Degree, Information Technology (Computer Science)   | 09/2001 - 06/2003 |
|--|-------------------|
| Kaunas University of Technology                              |                   |
| Bachelor's Degree, Information Technology (Computer Science) | 09/1997 – 06/2001 |
| Kaunas University of Technology                              |                   |